Hi, my name's generous nova senior program manager in the hyper scale
...io team and I'm here
today's talk about designing and sizing a global scale telemetry platform and measure event hubs.
Today we're going to cover what telemetry really is especially in the cloud context why it's
so important now however has makes it easy.
And, how to scale your telemetry for global application...end with how
...services add to your telemetry pipeline to give you more value?
...never been more important...it is now especially with cloud
computing it's more necessary than ever was in the past is also more valuable.
But, it's also more complex than it's ever been...a greater challenge than it's ever been.
So, how did telemetry become so complex it's really a simple concept just track what's going on
and where?
We really have to go back a little time travel here and see where this came to be if we look in the
...days we see the main-frame architecture which is common for computer systems
everything was in one place there was one clock that ruled everything was very easy to make sure everything
was in order of the terminal screen the green screen here on this was never actually even
a client itself it had no capabilities of its own wasn't usually even on a
network so this is a fairly easy system to implement telemetry and tracking.
After that and...not quite so old dayswe got in the client server architecture and,
this actually broke the telemetry into two different places client telemetry based on what the user
was doing what they were experiencing and server telemetry.
More recently that broke out into three...architecture tiered architecture three
...being most common and we divided the application server from something like database server the
most common approach and, now we had a proliferation of logs their
...in the client their logs on the application server...different logs in the database
server and, to makes even worse you have many clients each with their own logs and many
application servers database servers you scale this architecture out which is one of its key points
...it so useful.
More recently we've moved and, still very popular...enterprise space and this actually
compounds...problem even worse we have more of an integration approach
and many systems tied together through some sort of integration
platform and each of these systems are usually tiered architecture of their own so now you have
a logs that you don't even know about in places you don't know about and,
it's very hard to figure out exactly what's happening when you look for problems in the system
closest usually get is tracing what's happening integration layer which is only part of the problem.
Then we...it's cloud now it's not so clear cloud workloads are very
...you might have scaling up and down automatically in your cloud
Components can be running in different...might be services that you don't run yourself and
you use from others are going to...things like paths services
...service with...service so you have different types of
logs with different characteristics but they're all still necessary for
...system undoubtedly...his is improved...computing landscape
increased our agility...capabilities you look at small companies today can
go to global scale with very few employees you can think of some of the most famous
startups in the last few years in that way but,
visibility measure ability have often come at a price when moving to the
cloud especially if you don't plan for carefully and,
this really shows itself in any of these architectures when someone says it's
...what you do when someone comes to you and says
...in distributed computing system and cloud...the ultimate edge of distributed
...it's really hard to see what slow means
...you have one of extreme which is the user and then one extreme which is individual service
components or even physical components in that in that system so before I talk about
that and demise and moment for the day which is that what you can't measure you can't manage
and really that's about continuous improvement and quality management so,
you can always see how your systems are reacting the good news is that event...makes telemetry really, really
easy even a cloud scale it's easy to ploy...scale?
It's easy to integrate with other services or to write to in read from and
it's very cost-effective.
Let's walk through a very simple example let's
say fictitious company walk about it would be a dog walking service matches
dog walkers with pet owners in need of walk the walks actually for the
...not pet owners so, be like
...for...I...service not too different from this for scheduling
who watch my diagram out-of-town actually could use this right now so,
when you look at...typical applet this is going to
have some sort of mobile component usually there's going to be user so there's a
user using the system that's why it exists you can have a series of cloud services that
allows application function...probably...api
...it some sort of compute layer behind that almost certainly some sort of database
like...leisure some sort of storage notifications and
probably some external servicesthat...may not control and they may not be part of
measure for things like I don't know credit card charges other things like that so,
let's think about what this system really
looks like they're actually three different aspects of telemetry going on here?
The first is user journey this is
important thing track especially from a sort of a qualitative standpoint in how your users
are experiencing your application separate from that is client app performance this
is also really critical you can make a good decisions
or bad decisions based on how your application is performing...the client and then finally there's
a service performance which really encapsulates a whole lot of this it's easy to say this is one
system but they're really three distinct aspects of telemetry and it's very tempting to
...them in different ways.
This actually gets even more complicated because you might think that
well this isn't too much workload this isn't too big of an application it's not going
to be doing too much but if you think about the user journey so one entry and user
journey logging would be booking someone to walk my dog to do that I'm probably going to have to
...client several times I'd say probably six different
...the app interactions of between sending requests and receiving responses
presenting menus to the user things like that and...the service back-end for that is probably going to have
to forty different service operations for those six requests so across
the six requests so when you look at this you actually start piling up a tremendous
amount of telemetry already and you've ...more
complicated by having different aspects of telemetry which are all useful to you but even for a small
applications like for instance this is app in one big metro area you might have ten
thousand users who interacts twice today with the application.
And, really produce forty-seven events per interaction
you're actually talking about nine hundred forty thousand things to
...per day so, that's actually get in be a pretty big number, you know,
this goes from being beyond what you could just figure out really easily and casually to being
a bit of a challenge and now imagine if you didn't have ten thousand users imagine if you are in a lot of
markets good million users, you know,
keep adding...that andyou actually get into this place where your events will actually
trigger chain reaction of other events...you can see where that's going to
...not anywhere good actually.
In the past most the logging in our systems actually I want to see past I'd say
current currently most logging is done by
each component separately so you get you to get some sort of move in a while ago to
use logging frameworks at least on the service side...those are really useful but,
even when you...it's really independent logging independent on each server in
the system independent on each service in the system and it's really up to the system
administrators to collect those logs to shuffle them back together and try and
make sense out of them to see what's going on and, that can be a big...usually only happens
when something's gone wrong when someone says it's slow and you have to start figuring out what's going
wrong so this really makes a telemetry logging in current context viewed
more as a troubleshooting process...hubs changing this event...provides
ad centralized logging service that is cloud scale and has
built-in partitioning semantics which is the key to the scale
model?
This is a partition consumer model so what makes something a partition
consumer model it's a model that removes locks so you're moving away from
the central locking and contention model which would be can
competing consumer model into the partition consumer model
it scales out with more partitions rather than up there's always an upper limit to
how you can scale something and,
...cloud scales all about scaling out so,...really it's a logical opposite
of competing consumers and anything involving locking so databases things like that are going to be
your examples or your typical competing...they'll have a finite point which...to?
So, how does partition consumer work how does this work in about how does event hums really enable
...scale that we claim that it does event
...is actually made up of a set of partitions in each
of those partitions actually contains independent buffer of events within it?
Those events are ordered from oldest
newest and they really are functioning independently so,
partition one is unawares events in partition...
Event producers don't actually see the partitions normally they just send advanced into an event hub.
A couple choice about how to do that actually two choices they can do three http or
...qb and.
They can also have some other features like using a partition key to group
their events together not they pick which partition those...go-to
...they'll know that...events are always together for downstream systems to consume this can
be really useful for data locality so that if you need to do stream processing
or moving averages or anything like that all the events for a particular publisher in the same place when
...reading out of events of an...reading works a little bit differently and
this is where the partition consumer part comes event receivers are all readers
...consumers and they all access event hubs through a consumer group.
The collection of readers for each partition...event...is called
the consumer group and each partition does need...reader in order to read the entire stream.
This means that none of the readers are competing with each other to read that stream
...exclusively reading that stream.
You can actually use consumer groups have multiple
sat of readers reading the entire stream again each reader reading one partition within
that consumer group so this enables a sort of a pubs sub semantically for this
is the responsibility of the readers to keep track of where they are and that stream within
that consumer group within that partition so each consumer group can have separate offsets
their reading their streams from.
Setting events to...is very easy also here's an example of sending http post
to have a I chose this just because it's the easiest to read and,
because I don't natively speak in qb although I'm getting close so,
we do have the to protocols here http or...qb
...you choose depends on the usage that you're going after and
wearing your telemetry stack you're going to be if you're going to be on service side
...lot-of chatty telemetry it's almost always a good
...using qb it's a very sophisticated protocol
...message queuing protocol that has things like credit base flow
control has an open tls sessions you can send multiple events...having to do
...handshake over again it's really powerful and, we do provide the
http for in graphically so because a lot of devices and,
things and, avce use http
in know http and if you're actually doing very sparse communication like that to
...day things...the mobile app are you might actually be better off with http here you can see
the post just goes to a specific address this is
a mice specific event hub in here I'm setting authorization header which is just a
...token and a content type
then I put in some brokered properties so these are header properties for the message you can put
...under this brokered properties any basic type any primitive typed you like
and you can see the json message that I've put in here which is the http body
of...has actually look at the body so we don't do
any processing with it we never cracking open you can send whatever you want to can be encrypted it doesn't matter it
won't changer performance that's one of the reasons ...services able scale so well.
So, when you look at an overall pipeline for processing events measure
this is sort of the canonical architecture
...going to look like you can have event producers on one side of these could be applications they
can be devices they can be other services and,
they're going to be sending events to some place to be logged this can be through direct
sense to event...quite common especially for larger devices
are ip capable devicesthey can use cloud gateways to do some sort of protocol
translation perhaps a web api or something and,
then they can also use field gateways for when you get more into io
t type scenarios which this specific scenario walking through here isn't but
a lot of our users actually uses for the next stage and that is event
hubs this is really the in graphs service...is the ingestion
broker it's going to let the messages flow in and buffer them here to protect
the downstream components your pipeline which can be other services they might be compute
...they might be stream analytics which I'll touch on a little bit later
then after that you're going to get to things like long-term storage and presentation to users
and, actions you can take on this on this telemetry so,
the important thing to know when you look at a pipeline for event processing is
...pipeline is only as strong as the weakest link with it and that is why event
hubs is so important for building scaleable telemetry pipeline because sense it's a
buffer disconnects the upstream so the in grafting events from the downstream or
consumers of those events so if you have a flood of in...over-loaded your?
...without that if you don't have something that's a buffer
in-between your publishers of events in your consumers
...you're very likely going to get some pretty nasty scale problems
...will break and what's the right way to say in elegant fashion the sort of fall over.
So, the first-place start thinking about scale is really in the center of this pipeline although it's not
them the only place you have to think about scale in the entire pipeline so let's talk about how
...have skills...really
...mechanisms for this one we've talked about a little bit is partitions,
partitions are set...have creation time and they're really not so
much about scale in the event have as scale downstream the event the
...partitions is really fundamentally about the maximum degree of downstream
parallelism in more simple terms I guess that means how many active
readers you're going to have reading from that telemetry stream at one-time recalling
that each reader needs to be reading from one partition in order for it to be not
a competing consumer in order for to be a partition consumer model so partitions are really
more about downstream parallelism than they are about...
Event...themselves are really governed by throughput units throughput unit is a variable reserved
capacity it's variable in that it's a available hourly
you reservist and you're paying for it before so you reserve it for that
hour or as many hours you want and entitles you to in
gras one megabytes per second of telemetry or one thousand events per second
so that's the amount coming in whichever those limits you hit first is going to limit for that throughput unit.
Also entitles you to egress it to megabytes per second or two thousand events per
second so, we do throttle on both of these.
Throughput units are name space wide what really means is that namespaces for the top-level container
in-service process...is what event...part of
...so the capacity the reserving throughput
units is divided among all the event hubs within your name space if you only have one of an have that
makes...pretty easy just for that one.
Importantly over edges are throttled and their throttled evenly across event
...if you have multiple namespaces or multiple...hubs and even if you have multiple
active readers and writers it's not that whoever got their first gets all
the capacity it's that when we see that your exceeding your limited of reserve throughput
...throttle all
centres or all receivers based on which metric your exceeding so it's a lot fairness built into the
throttled which is also important for protecting your downstream system and protecting
your upstream senders in fact so you don't really sort of...yourself with telemetry?
How you scale throughput units are a couple ways to do
this one is the hourly way that I mentioned it's through the portal or
through rest call you can select anywhere between one and twenty throughput
units this actually enables you to scale-up to
twenty thousand events per second in graphs that's pretty big, you know,
one kilobyte twenty megabytes per second regress it's a pretty big though amount of...that comes out
...one-point-six something billion events per day so,
you're already started...pretty big numbers if you need more that and we do have customers anymore
than that we do a grant blocks of twenty throughput units at a time up
to one hundred you need to do a support ticket to do this rights manager portal but, when you do this
...no longer variable hourly charge it's a fixed charge all the time one thing keep in mind though
...the throughput...is only part of the cost of event hubs you also pay for egress in
graphs actually comes out to be the bigger number so-if you have throughput units...not filling
them up it's not really that big of a deal because the bigger numbers the actual events your publishing?
Finally if you need more than that and we do have a couple customers the
to we have a lot more internally but we have some public
ones we can talk about options for two hundred fifty megabytes per
second five hundred megabytes per second her gigabyte per second so if you really need that you need
to work with us this is not a short-term commitment sort of thing this does require long-term commitments and
partnership and planning but, we can grant you that capacity.
So, now that you have the basics of how your skate...scaling a single event
...single name space let's talk about how you're actually scaling your telemetry
...again remembering the center that pipeline is about hubs
Really throughput units are going to be your ultimate capacity cap so that's going to be your limit that
...be what you'll hit first at least and, it's important remember that you should size
for reasonable expected mid-term value this is cloud you can change it,
you know,
you can't change the number of partitions but you can create another event have nothing stops
you from that and,
it's really important not to plan for some sort of maximum optimistic long-term theoretical
scale limit that you might hit some day if everything goes great because you know,
why not do that that's kinda how the main framework to,
you know, that's a mentality...is trying to scale-up rather than out so,
this really ties you into decisions that you may not may not be happy with the future
...futures totally unknown to...you're starting out...building your service and you know,
it will change so important things keep in mind this is software, you know,
it should be soft each be flexible don't try and think about it like hardware it's kinda one of the dangers of these
building architectural analogies that people often uses software and,
then finally let's talk about real scale now I would think about scaling
your telemetry pipeline and your application general the way that we scale asher
or at least I can speak pretty confidently to the way we scale service
...asher and that's the concept of scale unit so what is a scale you it's
...independent vertical slice...that's built-in designed and tested to
support...specific...workload so that could be a number of users number devices
...amount of traffic and it
is complete vertical independent sliceusing scale...a good idea we do it for a few
reasons one of them is geo proximity especially if you're doing something like an app that users
are using interactively you want to have the latency times those users bs as
low as possible so putting your app in different locations around the world in different
...your datacenters regions will
make it much more responsive it also gives you better availability...a disaster
in one region might bring down...region if it's a big enough disaster something like an earthquake but,
you actually bison diversification by placing your application around the world
sort of like investing, you know,...diversification is the only free-lunch and,
finally you get the ability to...up an out when you use this sort of scale
unit model you can scale-up by making an individual scale unit bigger giving
it more throughput units more compute instances whatever your resources your bumping against
you need and you can scale it out by putting more of those throughput units in the same
regent or into more and more geographic regions so the what is a soc like when you actually
deploy this it's pretty easy and it's getting a lot easier now with
our new arm in a resource providers measure you basically just stamp
out the exact application exec stack in different places around the worldso,
this gives you again all those three attributes that I talked about the really useful
for-you about availability about proximity...about independent scale?
So, in this case this is exactly what this look like having datacenter spread around the world where users are.
So, how much can you really scale with this approach let's just not even get in the
call model let's think about just pure telemetry pipeline stuff we can stuff we've...stuff to work
in public so you probably don't have to call anyone before you have to call the event...team and,
let's think about for skill units round-the-world from the previous slide?
If you to rtwelve throughput units per scale unit so, you're talking about a capacity for up to
twelve thousand messages a second in each these for...you're dealing with one kilobyte
events you're going to a two point eight million events per minute as
your upward limitthat's a pretty big aggregate throughput and,
that's going to give you four billion events per
day and change so that's pretty big and if you look at that in data size since these are
one kilobyte messages four-point-one terabytes of data that's it that's tremendous amount of
...your very quickly going to reach the point where processing that amount
of telemetry is actually becoming more of a challenge than actually acquiring that amount of
the telemetry that's another way the scale unit model is going to help,
you know,
it's breaking a big problem down into smaller problems and solving them...you can still
aggregate things after the first stage but this is really the best model to do this with.
Next I want to talk a little bit.
About reading...processing events so the first thing I want covers
event processor host this is an intelligent agent
for of reading from event hubs that we've built for a dot net clients or working on other
languages as well it has some really slick features in it so it has automatic load
balancing partition management meaning who owns which partition and, the
client-side checkpoint...client-side cursor capabilities that you require when working with event hubs so
this framework this agent makes is all very easy to work with ...
show you how easy I'm actually just can show you the code for this aren't even need
break individual studio at all actually fits on one side in a fairly
legible size...what you need to do is implement ivan processor it's a class
in-service bus library or interface sorry and,
it has three methods, methods are closing open asic and process
events asic I think you can gather probably what they mean and that we take a...
very importantly very seriously because it's really the only way to provide real scale so,
you can actually see here pretty simple methods pretty simple
parameters for them and, in a little bit further detail let's actually go look at what
...more realistic implementation of...events asic might look like so,
you saw on my http request earlier I was setting a type...type in
the header called booking I can actually peek into those properties here I mention we don't
open the message body the event body but you can see in the properties and you can use
that to drive what sort of logic you're going to implement here so in this case I'm looking for booking
...I'm actually dc realizing a json object into...class that I know
...of type booking and, then importantly at the bottom here you can actually see that I'm keeping a dictionary
of bookings so I'm doing some duplicate detection in here a little bit very primitive
duplicate detection and, I'm keeping message count and then I'm
calling that checkpoint asic this thing I talked about before.
Checkpoint a sink is in this case with no, overload...is just going to
...the last message in that innumerable of event data that came into this
call so
...checkpoint will say to event hubI'm confident...I
...finish all the data up to this specific point and you don't do it
every single message because you would quickly run into other limits things like storage
limits about how quickly your check pointing of recall that we are we are talking about thousands of
messages per second scaled out even potentially millions
messages per second so you need to be careful in how you're going to
checkpoint this does give you a lot flexibility still this is the way that if
you're processing stopped and restarted it-would...to restart on another node?
Now that you've got your class you actually...hosted somewhere and this is where the host name
in event processor host comes in handy of post part of the name
...and instances classes very simple it takes
...at five parameters so...be the host naming the name machine it's running on usually good use
...name or something for that you wanted to be unique value
...event have name that should be obvious enough the consumer group name so that's just a label for
...consumer group the connection string for both event have answer storage and I
mention storage piece earlier because of storage is not only where we're going to save
that offset for each partition reader it's actually where we're going to use the
leasing mechanism storage to control who is reading from which partition after
you instantiated event processor host all you do is call register
event processor asic and this is going to tell the host that this
is the class it needs to instantiate for each partition that it's going to
start reading from and we look at how that works runtime.
We can see that when something starts up in this case I'll say worker it could be
...service it could be a command-line application...be anything and it's got an instance of
event processor host after that register call that event processor
hosed instances going to look at the event...see how many partitions...and try to get
...and every single partition and since there's no one else reading right now it's going to
...for every single partition after requires
that least it's going to create an instance of your event processor for every
single partition this is subtle and getting sort of important on this point actually and then after
it has instantiated those to call open a sank and
then start calling process events asic so this is the point
at which the data is coming in you might have noticed earlier in that in
that code example that I wasn't doing any sort of thread save collections that's because I don't need
to because this agent is creating affinity between the instances
...processor and the partitions...reading from for that instance
so you don't have to do thread safe collections you don't have to do thread management
you you're really protected from a lot of that in fact by default that process
events a...won't actually called again until you return from it so this
q up messages behind it or...up batches behind it to be processed so this is
a very powerful mechanism and, it helps you keep messages in order it helps you
by avoiding thread locking...go very fast and,
then also it scales really well so when you create a second worker instance or
second command-line programmer whatever it is your reading this or
hosting this agent in it's going to do the same thing it's...can look at the about
...to see how many partitions there...try to get elise for every partition it
...it's going to see that there are no partitions available so it will
place reservation for some partitions it's a greedy algorithm so it once all the partitions
...get and, when the first worker comes back and tries to renew its
lease for all of these partitions
...leases...see some of them it could not review and
close a single be called on those and the second worker will now open up on that partition
and take over the processing so this actually scales up and impressive...to actually
scales back down so when you step down and go back to just one server the load
redistribute...over a this will happen pretty quick with only a few servers will happen in
... the...thirty-minute a thirty second cycle so, it'll be
couple minutes if you have many readers like thirty-two or something it'll take a few minutes and
...settle at a prettyreasonable level reasonable distribution between and, to see how well
this really scales and why this is designed so well for asher...such core adder stuff and I chose
worker instances for this if you make a service which I did for this?
Cloud service so worker roles that are processing my event
stream in deploy it you can go in the scale tab and that service and you can
...that you actually have some scale capabilities that are going
to make this even easier for you to use the best one by far so,
far at least is cpu and when you think about the type of work you're...be doing
it could bebounded by cpu or memory or network but,
very likely if you're doing heavy compute type stuff stream processing type stuff it's going to be
cpu bound and this...scale capability and measure gives you the ability to set
as you can see here how many instances I want running and,
then what my target cpu band is so that's both
a lower band lower limit and upper limit and I can see that I could set of scale-up
by and the wait time to wait before applying that scale again
and scale down by
...really cool about this is that you can actually make very expressive shapes over
...so that you can ramp up very quickly and ramp down very slowlyif you
...hiding a process and,
that's really useful...actually gets...more useful because you can have multiple schedules
creative for different scale times so for instance in that same portal
this clicking the schedules button are you can change
have different scales for day and night and different different
scale settings for weekends and weekdays so these are pretty...you can even do independent,
independent specific days so specific holidays or something that you want to have some sort of scale
for...gives you a really good capability of scaling your
compute if you're writing your own code using event processor host?
Which...code I would strong you strongly encourage you to use vent presser host but,
now I want to talk about something passes something
past writing coding getting more towards like real cloud...
...integration actually and that is event hubs and stream analytics
stream analytics is one of my favorite services actually they just
the ga recently and it's a stream processing service in the
...so what's that mean it's that it's true
...just like event hubs you don't install anything you don't have to
two-run anything yourself it's got dynamic scale much like about hubs to talk about a little
bit it has a domain specific language...very elegant based on a sequel and
makes very easy to make expressive statements about processing streams.
That language provides...esl prides a number of when doing functions that are very
useful when doing stream calculations are stream processing specially for things like anomaly
...alert detection and integrates directly with
perhaps which is of course my favorite thing it does using
...everything that...must use...access it and,
this is because it service to service and that gives is really good performance characteristics.
So, creating stream analytics job is really, really simple
they're really just sort of three things you have to...input and output
and query creating the job is really easy you just go in
the portal click-throughdata servicesgo through stream analytics
quick create new just given a name in this case this is where telemetry
changes from how it has been in the past and this is where becomes
the switching point from having a telemetry...cost center
having telemetry ba revenue center or something that makes...service interact,
you know, of better through a to changes that you can do through the way
your systems work not just in retrospect so in this case I'm creating a booking
intervention service so, this would be for if I'm having trouble
booking or if a lot of booking events come in a short time window and, you know,
that's either because I'm doing something on expected in the application
of the applications in my hand the performing away I
...to...or potentially through some sort of fraud so once you've created your stream
...job like I said three steps you'll see there's no input for it
...just click that input button and you get to choose if it's going to be data stream
...reference data is very simple jobs some
stick to data stream you'll see the default on there is event
hub that's what I like it is you can do blob storage as well but, event hubs, you know,
it's made for speed is me for scale so it's the fault for reason and from there you can actually browse
two-year has your subscription and pick which event have you want to read from and you can
actually also provide which policy want to use this case I'm kinda doing a bad example
...using the really the admin policy you should make a policy just for
your specific listeners so you can make one that only has rights to listen to your event
...to read and that way that the stream
analyst job itself can't actually do anything more to your
...habit doesn't need admin access and, then finally you get to choose which
consumer group by default it's going to be one called default surprisingly enough in this poorly can actually
create new consumer group it's generally good idea to use different consumer groups for each job?
And, then the last step is that you're going to choose what this input
sterilization format isyou have a few choices here I'm picking json because that's what we
saw messages earlier in my encoding...be uta and now the query for the
asa job again of really quite simple
there are a few little things left learn about it but not much fear at all comfortable
...you do a select you can actually see these names are coming
from like customer name is actually coming from when ...original message...json field in
...called customer name...my name and, what I'm doing here is I'm grouping these
in a tumbling window which is a specific type of when doing function over five-minute
window grouping by customer name and I'm looking for booking events
they have occurred more than three times in the last five minutes so
that's just whatever random logic I've...now once you have this here this is actually
...that part about this ...query and you can actually go back to
your input you'll notice there's a little,
little highlighted box I put on there highlights on the portal to sample data
box this is a way to actually download some of the data in your event...a so
...can test with this is a feature that stream analytics private because they wanted it and actually
...of an has quite a bit too do be a little careful this...download a whole lot data so
pick really what you need not everything in there if you're writing a lot of data the last step is
...be creating output for stream alex job this is even simpler than the input
one you can pick a variety of sources here including picking event hubs which is what I'm showing on
the screen I actually like the idea of picking event hubs because enables sort of a pipes and
filter's...too many people I think he looked...first sort of the
centre of everything and it's the big fat pipe...absolutely everything
and in some cases that's a good pattern in some it's...you might have
specificprocessors or workloads that just want to read
...event pipe and that is actually a great thing to use stream analytics for or
...some sort of filter between the pipes that are event...so,
that you can have downstream readers just have dedicated a sort of an
...or stream...that they can read from and, also you
...cereals...you can change sterilization at this point where you can keep it how it was?
Then importantly the last sort of peace and talk about for event hubs about scaling
or for stream analytics is about scaling the scaling model for stream analytics is very much like
the scaling model for event hubs I don't think that's...and,
they basically both go through blocks of one megabyte per second throughput so,
you know, on this on the screen and asher you...that drop down for streaming units
...that job and, it goes to some big number bigger than the throughput units does
so forty-something I think is what ice online this morningso, it's pretty slick pretty
...capability you can make jobs for all sorts of things and like I mentioned,
you know, this allows you to turn your telemetry from sort of a...sort of
troubleshootingpiece that you sorta have to have well,
if you want to stay...at least you have to have into something that you can really provide new services with
you can really build new things on these could be failure alerts these could be anomaly or
fraude detections they could be customer interventions really this is whereaddress making
...easy for you to decide how to do
...business which is which is probably not writing the cloud platform which is what we're doing so,
the question is less of more where your to
...take you then we'll take your telemetry?
This picture my bike there so,
I encourage you take a look at are getting started guides both for event
hubs which your accessible right from the measure portal and for stream analyticsalso
...here is a link for the blog for...best team we boggle kinds of
fun stuff on there and finally my twitter handle if you want tofollow all the fun fund
service...stuff that we do on the team thanks-very-much this...been.
Cloud scale telemetry processing...